I wrote "Ting Cook" in Korean and
gave it as a gift, and they really loved it.
Brother, I found out on the day itself this time, so I could
n't bring the gift in advance.  You'll still give me a good answer, right
?
get out.
hello.  This is Ibi.  I had a great
opportunity to interview Tim, the former CEO of Apple, last time
.  However, this time, for
those who have watched many Apple keynotes, Almahan
Craig Patrick had the opportunity to interview Apple's
Vice President of Software Engineering
.  Honestly, if you
like electronics and have watched some Apple Keynotes but
don't know this person, you're a fool.   This
is because, while Apple has
announced a lot of software-related content at its keynotes, it is also
very famous for showing many entertaining moments within those presentations
.  Of course, it would have been
more interesting to meet Apple CEO John Toners, but with the
iPhone Duo released this time, there are actually quite a
few people who were surprised more by the software than the hardware.   As for
the hardware, there are actually
many things that other foldable phones have already demonstrated
.  But then again, regarding the software, I was
personally very curious about it because it definitely generated more buzz than the hardware due to Apple's perverse obsession and design
.  But then, just as the
keynote ended, a great
opportunity arose to interview Vice President Federgi
.  To start with, the truth is that
Apple interviews are only
15 minutes long, including the interview time, so realistically, it is difficult to ask overly sensitive
questions or questions related to English secrets
.  Even though they were busy and being careful with the new product, they took the
time to meet me. So, I made sure to
ask them some questions while maintaining mutual courtesy, and I’d like to share the
details of my interview with you today
.  Let's take a
look together.  To me, from me,
about...
Last time I conducted an interview with Cook, and
this time I'm really glad to meet the idol of Apple Keynote. Thank
you. [Laughs] You
show such a witty and humorous side in every Keynote appearance, so you have a lot of fans in Korea as well
.
So, getting to the main point, the
first thing I want to ask is this:
when the new iPhone was released, everyone was really fascinated by the emotional animations when opening and closing it. I am
curious about the intention behind creating that.
in love with this
animation.  I I think
we wanted to create
something that was
uh the most natural
expression of what's
happening on the
device, which is
you're transparently
moving from an
experience on the
front to the
inside.  And so we
really wanted
continuity because
we expect people to
move many times
between starting
something in one and
transitioning to the
other.  And so the
idea that as you
lift it up that
you're suddenly just
seen through a
window into what's
below feels like the
most natural thing.
When the iPhone Duo came out, I was hoping for
more freedom and extensive multitasking like the iPad, given that the screen was slightly larger, but
honestly, when I saw it in person, it was
n't quite that amazing.
So I am also
curious if there was an intention behind this.
iPhone duo as much
own thing.  you know,
it is not an
iPad.  Um it is a uh
amazingly versatile
uh and we wanted the
experience to be
very consistent uh
with what you would
expect uh as an
iPhone user.  And so
the model when it
opens up of
everything uh being
the experience being
very common between
the closed and open
states uh and the
model of interaction
being very
consistent was uh
very important to
us.  Um, we wanted to
make all those
interactions very
natural and fluid as
well.  Some of these
more complex window
management, organize
everything um are are
uh can be a
little tedious and
don't transition
well when you close
the device.
Everything changes.
We felt like
something that still
gave you, uh, as a
user, a great deal of
power to do the
things you want with
multitasking or
watching video and
using app
and easy to get into.
Another question is, when you think of the iPhone or other
smartphones, it is generally common to have a dock bar at the bottom, but
when the iPhone came out, it showed a completely new, perhaps new,
concept of UIX experience, which was really
surprising.  But I am curious
exactly which target audience was considered when
creating this.  Because
after I uploaded the content, I saw some questions asking if I had
n't considered left-handed people
.
Stretching out one or
squeezing down an
iPad.  We viewed it
as its own thing.  We
conceived of both
the hardware and the
interface at the
same time and uh
thought of many
alternatives and
realized that we
could create this
wonderful form
factor uh if we
adapted the
interface in a in a
allne and unique way
to take advantage of
moving content to
the spine uh making
it very reachable.
also making giving
your content the
full height of the
device.  And we think
this is uh really
vastly superior to
cases where people
have taken
traditional tall
phone UIs and then
just sort of push
them down uh and
left little space um
for content uh with
the content at the
bottom.  And so uh it
was very important
to us to optimize
the design for
exactly what this
form factor uh uh
demanded without any
uh concern about the
legacy.  And for
users who are
left-handed, uh
we've made a number
of adaptations.  For
instance, you can
push the keyboard
over to one side.  So
if you're holding
the device and you
want to do
one-handed uh
typing, you can do
that without
reaching across uh
the width of the
device.  Um and we
also find it's a
natural thing uh
certainly when the
device is open and
even when it's
closed to sometimes
operate with two
hands and the the
device of the
buttons along the
side make it really
easy to access
controls vertically
because the device
isn't so tall that
you can't reach
toward the top.
Is that the end?  Or one last question,
one more.  Ah, regarding the last
question, many
Apple fans were really looking forward to Apple's foldable phone, but since it was
released a bit later than competing brands, I am
curious to know if you could pick just one advantage to make up for that disappointment.
I think ason
apple we ar being
best and we weren't
this product until
we had something
that came together
in all elements to
our vision for this
and some of that
weve talked about
already with this
user experience I
think that's very
distinctive it's a
very ambitious
project to take the
whole operating
system and
experience and all
the built
applications and
frameworks and adapt
them to a whole new
framework.  I think
if you look at other
devices, other
people have sort of
taken whatever
operating system was
out there, throw it
onto the screen,
ship a product, uh
we wanted something
to take the time to
design something
great.  I think if
you look at the
quality of the
hardware, if you
look at the beauty
of that internal
display, uh how
perfectly flat it
is, uh it it these
are very distinctive
elements to the
experience, but for
us it's not about
individual little
features.  It's about
all coming together
in one totally
thought through
experience and
that's worth for
you.  thank you.
Ah, now that I've conducted this interview, the
15 minutes really flew by
.  Is it because of the spiritual power?
So, I actually expected to get a lot of Apple-style answers
.  But then, perhaps because Vice
President Padregi spoke quite honestly, he also made
me
laugh.  Anyway, that’s all for today. I think it’s
good that Apple always creates opportunities like this to speak directly.
Although I couldn’t ask all the questions I wanted, I will try
using the iPhone myself once it is released and take my time to figure it out
.
I heard it a lot yesterday, too. Ah, even
when I'm running right now, if I just go a little further, then that
[laughter]